William Johnston

22 Beatty Street, Balgowlah Heights Sydney, NSW 0416 385 080 willjohnston1992@gmail.com

June 7, 2016
Russel Burgess
Senior Coordinator Apprentice and Intern Programs
Qantas

Dear Mr. Burgess,

Re: Qantas Engineering Winter School Program

After receiving notice of the Qantas Engineering Winter Student Program, I would like to apply for an internship within your program. Currently, I am in my final year of my combined Masters of Biomedical Engineering / Bachelor of Mechatronic Engineering (Hons) degree. I believe that I would be a great asset to the Qantas team due to the skills and experiences I have gained from my time at the University of New South Wales.

Throughout my time at The University of New South Wales I developed several skills required for the engineering workplace. I learnt how to think analytically and to solve problems with different approaches. I became very familiar with the design process, participating in several successful design tasks within the university. A large portion of my education focused on the management aspects of engineering. I was able to practice my own leadership skills and communication skills through group work. These skills will enable me to be a productive member of the Qantas team.

Studying mechatronic engineering has given me a strong fascination for engineering systems, especially in their integration with other systems as well as the efficiencies in the way they operate. Working at Qantas is of special interest to me owing to the opportunity to work with such large and complex systems. I would thoroughly enjoy the opportunity to learn about these systems at Qantas and to contribute to them in some way.

I look forward to discussing my application with you.

Thank you for your consideration, William Johnston

William Johnston

willjohnston1992@gmail.com 0416385080

Core Skills

· CAD (Solidworks)	• Matlab	· Problem Solving
· Engineering Design	· Web Development	· Project Management
· Team Development	·Communication	· Independent work
· Object Oriented Programming	·Java	·Python
	· C++	\cdot MySQL

Education

Master of Biomedical Engineering University of New South Wales	2011-2016
Bachelor of Engineering University of New South Wales Majoring in Mechatronic Engineering	2011-2016
Higher School Certificate SCECGS Redlands	2010

Employment History

Knife Hand, Millin's Fine Food Butcher

Aug. 2012 - Present

- Responsible for assisting senior butchers with meat preparation, sales and shop wide cleaning, over the last six months assisted in the training of two new knife hands.
- Developed valuable communication skills, corresponding with both colleagues and customers.
- · Improved work standards to ensure customer satisfaction.

Labourer Jan. 2011 - Present

- · Laboured on several construction sites throughout this time.
- Learned the importance of innovation, a lot of repetitive tasks with the opportunity to develop new and improved methods.